Inventory of the Papers of Duke and Duke 1854-1956
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
- General Office Correspondence and Cases
  - Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corporation, Ltd. 1923 (Box 184)
  - Pacific Fire Insurance Company 1932 (Box 185)
  - Preferred Accident Insurance Company 1929-1941, 3 folders (Box 185)
  - Prudential Insurance Company of America 1936-1939 (Box 185)
  - Railway Employees Insurance 1939 (Box 185)
  - St. Paul Fire and Marine Insurance Company 1925 (Box 185)
  - Shelby Mutual Plate Glass and Casualty Company 1931 (Box 185)
  - Underwriters Casualty Company 1930 (Box 185)
  - Zurich Insurance Company 1930's, 7 folders (Box 185)
  - Bound Insurance Records
    - Insurance register for Germania Fire Insurance Company 1901-1923 (Oversize 15)
    - Insurance ledger for City of New York Insurance Company 1914-1921 (Oversize 16)
    - Workmen's compensation forms arranged by company 1944-1950 (Oversize 17)
    - Insurance registers for Camden Fire Insurance Association, National Fire Insurance Company, New York Underwriters' Agency, and Rochester German Insurance Company 1902-1924 (Oversize 18-21)
- Records of the Insurance Agency of Charlottesville
  - William F. Carter Bankruptcy 1919-1922 (Box 186)
  - Insurance Agency of Charlottesville 1924-1930, 1944 (Box 186)
  - Alliance Insurance Company-St. Paul Fire and Marine Insurance Company 1923, 26 folders (Box 186)
  - Chevrolet Motor Company- Jmiscellaneous 1923, 39 folders (Box 187)
  - W. J. Perry Corporation-Dr. W. G. Wiatt 1923, 34 folders (Box 188)
  - H. D. Weade- N-Z miscellaneous 1923, 7 folders (Box 189)
  - Miscellaneous bills, insurance business correspondence 1923, 4 folders (Box 189)
  - Accident Insurance- Amiscellaneous 1924, 10 folders (Box 189)
  - Bale-Snedeker Company- FMiscellaneous 1924, 43 folders (Box 190)
  - Thomas Gemmell, Inc.-J miscellaneous 1924, 27 folders (Box 191)
  - Mrs. L.W. Kirby- Omiscellaneous 1924, 27 folders (Box 192)
  - E. B. Parrott- Rmiscellaneous 1924, 21 folders (Box 193)
  - St. Louis Sticker Company- Wmiscellaneous 1924, 32 folders (Box 194)
  - Laura E. Yardley-Casualty Insurance 1924, 2 folders (Box 195)
  - Ymiscellaneous 1924 (Box 195)
  - J. B. Alexander-B miscellaneous 1925, 31 folders (Box 195)
  - Calendars- Fmiscellaneous 1925, 47 folders (Box 196)
  - Gladys Garth- Jmiscellaneous 1925, 42 folders (Box 197)
  - W. W. Keenan- Mmiscellaneous 1925, 43 folders (Box 198)
  - National Bank of Charlottesville-W. J. Perry Corporation 1925, 18 folders (Box 199)
  - Phoenix Insurance Company- Smiscellaneous 1925, 54 folders (Box 200)
  - B. F. Tabb- Wmiscellaneous 1925, 35 folders (Box 201)
  - Albemarle Telephone Company-Scott Coleman 1926, 41 folders (Box 202)
  - Commerce Insurance Company-Thomas Gemmell Company 1926, 46 folders (Box 203)
  - James B. Gibson-R. T. Minor, Jr. 1926, 45 folders (Box 204)
  - Miscellaneous-W. J. Perry Corporation 1926, 21 folders (Box 205)
  - W. J. Perry Corporation-St. Paul Fire and Marine Insurance Company 1926, 24 folders (Box 206)
  - Elsie May Smith-Charles Zehab 1926, 37 folders (Box 207)
  - Advertisement-General Accident Assurance Company 1927, 34 folders (Box 208)
  - S. M. Gould-Ocean Accident Guarantee Corporation Ltd. 1927, 26 folders (Box 209)
  - O miscellaneous-Virginia Building and Loan Association Inc. 1927, 35 folders (Box 210)
  - Virginia Inspection and Rating Bureau- Zmiscellaneous 1927, 12 folders (Box 211)
  - Insurance Policies for The Associated Companies, Carolina Insurance, Dixie Fire Insurance, Fireman's Fund Insurance, Globe and Rutgers Fire Insurance, Great American Insurance, Hartford Fire Insurance, and Imperial Assurance 1923-1927, 11 folders (Box 212)
  - Insurance Policies for the Liverpool and London and Globe, Maryland Casualty, New Hampshire Fire Insurance, Rhode Island Insurance, Ocean Accident and Guarantee, the Phoenix Insurance, Royal Insurance, and St. Paul Fire and Marine Insurance 1923-1927, 13 folders (Box 213)
  - Insurance Policies for Miscellaneous Companies 1924-1926, 10 folders (Box 214)
  - Insurance Reports for the Carolina Insurance Company, Dixie Fire Insurance, and Globe Underwriters Agency 1923-1927, 6 folders (Box 215)
  - Insurance Reports for Imperial Assurance, and Maryland Casualty 1923-1927, 7 folders (Box 216)
  - Insurance Reports for Phoenix Insurance, Ocean Accident and Guarantee, Great American Insurance, St. Paul Fire and Marine, and others 1923-1927, 10 folders (Box 217)
  - Bound Insurance Records
    - Register of insurance policies arranged by companies 1925-1927 (Oversize 22)
    - Insurance register, J. R. Gillis, agent 1921-1923 (Oversize 23)
    - Insurance register, Granite State Fire Insurance Company, Henry Rubin Insurance Agency 1925 (Oversize 24)
    - Insurance Ledger-Journal 1926-1927 (Oversize 25)
- Financial Records of the Duke Family (see also Bound Financial Records)
  - Alexander and Mill Property 1926 (Box 218)
  - Chancellor Lot 1922-1946, 10 folders (Box 218)
  - Charlottesville School District land 1863-1892 (Box 218)
  - Clermont Hotel/Jefferson Hotel Property and miscellaneous bills 1925-1940, 3 folders (Box 218)
  - Coal companies bank receipts 1888-1891 (Box 219)
  - Coal companies: Ceredo Land Association 1889 (Box 219)
  - Coal companies: Crockett's Cove Coal and Iron Company 1912-1923 (Box 219)
  - Coal companies: First National Bank of Lynchburg 1890 (Box 219)
  - Coal companies: Kentucky Coal Company 1891-1935, 11 folders (Box 219)
  - Coal companies: Kycoga Land Company 1935-1953 (Box 220)
  - Coal companies: Ohio and Big Sandy Coal Company 1890-1901, 16 folders (Box 220-221)
  - Coal companies: Pike County Coal Company 1889-1924, 13 folders (Box 221-222)
  - Coal companies: United Thacker Coal Company 1925-1941 (Box 222)
  - Country Club property 1921, 1939-1940, 2 folders (Box 222)
  - Court Square Building 1929-1955, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Edith R. Duke Estate 1920's (Box 222)
  - ERD Will and Statements from Kountze Brothers 1921 (Box 222)
  - Jack F. S. Duke Bank Statements and Checks 1923-1924 (Box 222)
  - JFSD Estate 1933-1946 (Box 222)
  - Kathleen H. Duke Estate 1930; 1947, 2 folders (Box 222)
  - R.T.W. Duke Estate 1898-1899 (Box 222)
  - R.T.W. Duke, Jr. Tax Receipts, Stocks 1889-1894 (Box 222)
  - RTWD, Jr. Estate 1915-1937, 10 folders (Box 223)
  - R.T.W. Duke III v. Duke's Executors: Financial Records 1938 (Box 223)
  - RTWD III Correspondence with siblings re estate 1929-1938; 1942 (Box 223)
  - RTWD III: Hinds Shoe Company 1913, 2 folders (Box 224)
  - Mary Duke Financial Records 1926-1952, 6 folders (Box 224)
  - William E. and Lucy Lee Duke Bank Business 1927-1930 (Box 224)
  - WED Financial Records 1921-1954, 7 folders (Box 224, 225)
  - WED Home File 1950-1952 (Box 225)
  - WED Personal Insurance 1925-1954, 5 folders (Box 225)
  - WED Correspondence with Montgomery Ward 1929 (Box 225)
  - WED Notes (paid) 1948-1950, 2 folders (Box 225)
  - WED: Palace Garage (receipts) 1923 (Box 226)
  - WED Personal receipts 1923-1944 (Box 226)
  - WED Miscellaneous personal records 1925-1928, 2 folders (Box 226)
  - WED Taxes 1924-1952, 7 folders (Box 226)
  - WED Construction of Thomson Road House 1919 [1923-1927]-1940's, 6 folders (Box 226)
  - WED Telephone Bills 1953-1954 (Box 226)
  - WED Trust Fund 1930-1931 (Box 226)
  - WED Utilities 1946-1954 (Box 226)
  - WED Virginia Telephone and Telegraph Company Bills 1940's (Box 227)
  - Duke Family loans, trusts, forms 1934-1950 (Box 227)
  - Federal Apartments 1927-1945, 2 folders (Box 227)
  - First National Bank of Lynchburg 1925-1928 (Box 227)
  - Meadow Creek Property 1930-1930, 19 folders (Box 227, 228)
  - Miscellaneous maps and plats 1900-1950 (Box 228)
  - Monticello Wine Company 1915 (Box 228)
  - Rosalie Slaughter Morton Financial Papers 1918-1926, 4 folders (Box 228)
  - Park Street Property 1937-1950's, 2 folders (Box 228)
  - Slaughter Estates 1887-1952, 10 folders (Box 229)
  - Timberlake Property 1930 (Box 229)
  - Records of Civic Activities
    - American Arbitration Association 1929-1940, 2 folders (Box 230)
    - American Arbitration Society 1941 (Box 230)
    - American Bar Association 1933-1938, 2 folders (Box 230)
    - American Legion 1920-1921, 2 folders (Box 230)
    - Army and Navy Club 1933 (Box 230)
    - Baptists [re wills] 1947 (Box 230)
    - Charlottesville Bar Association c. 1923 (Box 230)
    - Democratic Party 1921, 1928, 2 folders (Box 230)
    - Gallop Poll 1944-1945 (Box 230)
    - International Association of Insurance Counsel 1932, 4 folders (Box 230, 231)
    - Library Correspondence 1934 (Box 231)
    - Masons (RTWD, Jr. and WED) 1900-1920, 1935-1936, 2 folders (Box 231)
    - Officers' Reserve Corps Bulletins c. 1930's (Box 231)
    - Phi Epsilon Pi 1907-1912, 1924, 2 folders (Box 231)
    - Salvation Army 1920's (Box 231)
    - St. Paul's Church and Church Fund 1906-1910 (Box 231)
    - School Statistics, Charlottesville area 1915 (Box 231)
    - Sigma Nu fraternity 1936 (Box 231)
    - University Athletic Association 1927, 1929 (Box 231)
    - University of Virginia Alumni Bulletin 1901 (Box 231)
    - University of Virginia Alumni Fund 1941 (Box 231)
    - University of Virginia Development Fund 1947 (Box 231)
    - Virginia Athletic Association 1920's (Box 231)
    - Virginia Bar Association 1926 (Box 231)
    - YMCA, University of Virginia 1924-1925 (Box 231)
    - Miscellaneous civic organizations 1910, 1922 (Box 231)
  - Miscellaneous Material
    - 1824 Almanac and other printed matter 1824-1908 (Box 232)
    - Transcriptions of letters from James Monroe to Egbert Watson 1829-1831 (Box 232)
    - Insurance Policy for the Mutual Assurance Society of Virginia 1855 (Box 232)
    - Insurance Policy for the Mutual Assurance Society of Virginia 1855 (Box 232)
    - Documents, re Civil War 1860-1920's (Box 232)
    - R.T.W. Duke's copy of the Congressional Directory for the 43rd Congress 1872 (Box 232)
    - Reuben Harlow's Mexican War documents 1887 (Box 232)
    - William R. Duke's copy of the Journal of the Virginia House of Delegates1901 (Box 232)
    - Miscellaneous material found in letterpress books 1900-1909 (Box 232)
    - Miscellaneous printed material 1900-1920's (Box 232)
    - Miscellaneous family memorabilia 1907, n.d. (Box 232)
    - WED's Spanish language exercise book and maps of France 1910-1930's (Box 232)
    - Biographical dictionary entry for Duke and Duke 1924 (Box 232)
    - Missionary materials from Rev. H.G.C. Hallock in Shanghai, China 1929 (Box 232)
    - Newspapers files under "French" 1929 (Box 232)
    - "Meadow Creek"--Christmas program c. 1929 (Box 232)
    - Duke family history 1930's (Box 232)
  - Photographs
    - Portrait of R.T.W., William R., and R.T.W. Duke, Jr. [1880's?]
    - Copy of photograph of RTWD, Jr. n.d.
    - [R.T. Walker Duke III?] in Army uniform c. WWI
    - RTWD, Jr.'s house at 616 Park Street in Charlottesville; Christmas tree inside the house n.d.
    - Lucy Marshall Duke, daughter of William E. Duke, on lawn with dog [1945]
    - Claude Lee's children [Lucy Lee became WED's wife] n.d.
    - Formal portrait of John F. Slaughter, Jr., relative [father? cousin?] of Edith R. Duke n.d.
    - Unidentified Duke family photos and negatives n.d.
    - Portrait of Micajah Woods 1879